Guide to the Records of The Pacific Car Demurrage, 1901-1946 JL020
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Pacific Car Demurrage Records,
1901-1946
JL020
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
11.5 Linear feet
Scope and Content
The Records of the Pacific Car Demurrage Bureau contains only records associated with business transactions including: receipted vouchers, payrolls, register of vouchers, cashbooks, time books, journals, and ledgers. Most of these are pasted into ledger books, which are old (dates range 1901-1946) and, in some cases, in poor condition.
Historical Note
The Pacific Car Demurrage Bureau also called the Pacific Car Service Bureau seems to have been a sort of collection agency for the different west coast railroad companies. The P.C.D.B. would be responsible for collectiong the fee that came due whena freight car was held beyond the reasonable time for loading or unloading of transported materials.
Provenance
Gift of the Pacific Car Demurrage Bureau to the Jackson Library of Business, 1973. Transferred to Special Collections in 1979.
Access Restrictions
None.
Pacific Car Demurrage Bureau; Business enterprises--California.; Business records.; Cashbooks.; Journals (bookkeeping); Ledgers.; Payrolls.
- Receipted Vouchers, 1901 July - 1902 May (Volume 1)
  - Vouchers #1-211 inclusive
  - Payroll - Pacific Car Service Bureau
  - Expense Accounts - Pacific Car Service Bureau
  - Cost of operating Bureau and distribution of expenses by railroads
- Receipted Vouchers, 1902 June - 1903 May (Volume 2)
  - Vouchers #212-274 inclusive and #1-193 inclusive
  - Payroll - Pacific Car Service Bureau
  - Expense Accounts - Pacific Car Service Bureau
  - Cost of operating Bureau and distribution of expenses by railroads
- Receipted Vouchers, 1903 June - 1904 May (Volume 3)
  - Vouchers #194-263 inclusive and #1-204 inclusive
  - Payroll - Pacific Car Service Bureau
  - Expense Accounts - Pacific Car Service Bureau
  - Cost of operating Bureau and distribution of expenses by railroads
- Receipted Vouchers, 1904 July - 1905 July (Volume 4)
  - Vouchers #224-267 inclusive and #1-167 inclusive
  - Payroll - Pacific Car Service Bureau
  - Expense Accounts - Pacific Car Service Bureau
  - Cost of operating Bureau and distribution of expenses by railroads
- Payroll and Receipted Vouchers, 1906 Apr - 1908 Mar (Volume 5)
  - SP #1-5 inclusive
  - Payroll #1A-24 inclusive
  - Vouchers #1A-416A inclusive
  - Cost of operating Bureau and distribution of expenses by railroads
- Receipted Vouchers, 1908 Apr - 1909 Apr (Volume 6)
  - SP #7-40 inclusive
  - Payroll #24-37 inclusive
  - Vouchers #417A-649A inclusive
  - Cost of operating Bureau and distribution of expenses by railroads
- Receipted Vouchers, 1909 May - 1910 Feb (Volume 7)
  - SP #41-49 inclusive
  - Payroll #38-47 inclusive
  - Vouchers #650A-862 inclusive
  - Cost of operating Bureau and distribution of expenses by railroads
- Payroll and Receipted Vouchers, 1910 Mar - 1910 Dec (Volume 8)
  - SP #7-40 inclusive
  - Payroll #24-37 inclusive
  - Vouchers #417A-649A inclusive
  - Cost of operating Bureau and distribution of expenses by railroads
- Statements Expenses Account and Distribution of Expense, 1901 July - 1924 Mar (Volume 9)
  - Refund claims
- Register of Vouchers, 1905 Sept - 1937 Feb (Volume 10)
- Register of Vouchers, 1922 Mar - 1937 Feb (Volume 11)
- Cash Book, 1901 July - 1905 Jan (Volume 12)
- Cash Book, 1909 July - 1915 May (Volume 13)
- Cash Book, 1915 June - 1921 Aug (Volume 14)
- Cash Book, 1921 Sept - 1927 Dec (Volume 15)
- Cash Book, 1928 Jan - 1934 Mar (Volume 16)
- Cash Book, 1934 Apr - 1940 June (Volume 17)
- Cash Book, 1940 July - 1946 Sept (Volume 18)
- Journal, 1909 July - 1919 Mar (Volume 19)
- Journal, 1919 Apr - 1926 May (Volume 20)
- Journal, 1926 June - 1932 Dec (Volume 21)
- Journal, 1933 Jan - 1939 Apr (Volume 22)
- Ledger, 1909 June - 1926 June (Volume 23)
- Ledger, 1926 July - 1942 Dec (Volume 24)
- Book (Volume 25)
  - Interest on Working Fund advanced by SPCo and AT&SF Ry Co, 1915 May - 1916 Mar
- Book (Volume 26)
  - Payroll sheets, 1926 June 1 - 1933 Dec 31
- Bank Book (Volume 27-1)
  - Wells Fargo Nevada National Bank, 1910 July 30 - 1919 Dec 31
- Bank book (Volume 27-2)
  - Payroll sheets, 1920 Jan 14 - 1929 Dec 31
- Bank Book (Volume 27-3)
  - Payroll sheets, 1930 Jan 2 - 1937 Nov 30
- Time Book - Monthly, 1906 Apr 1 - 1919 Dec 31 (Volume 27-4)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1910 Jan 1 - 1912 Dec 31 (Volume 27-5)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1913 Jan 1 - 1916 Dec 31 (Volume 27-6)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1917 Jan 1 - 1929 Apr 30 (Volume 27-7)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1917 Feb 1 - 1919 May 20 (Volume 27-8)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1920 May 1 - 1922 Apr 30 (Volume 27-9)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1922 May 1 - 1923 Oct 31 (Volume 27-10)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1919 Mar 21 - 1924 Mar (Volume 27-11)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1922 Oct 1 - 1925 Dec 31 (Volume 27-12)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1923 Nov 1 - 1925 Apr 30 (Volume 27-13)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1925 May 1 - 1926 June 30 (Volume 27-14)
- Time Book - Monthly, 1924 July 1 - 1939 Sept 30 (Volume 27-15)
- Time Book - Monthly - Revising Department, 1930 Jan 1 - 1934 May 31 (Volume 27-16)
- Time Book - Monthly - Revising Department, 1924 July 1 - 1929 Dec 31 (Volume 27-17)
- Time Book - Monthly (Volume 28)
- Payroll Bundle
  - 1911 Mar - 1912 June
  - 1912 Aug - 1912 Sept
  - 1913 Nov - 1916 Sept
  - 1916 Nov - 1917 Dec
  - 1919 July - 1919 Sept
  - 1919 Nov - 1919 Dec
  - 1920 May - 1921 May
  - 1921 July - 1921 Dec
  - 1922 Feb - 1922 Aug
  - 1922 Oct - 1922 Nov